The World is watching
Battle of the Year is a music, drama film directed by Benson Lee.
A down-on-his-luck coach is hired to prepare a team of the best American dancers for an international tournament that
attracts all the best crews from around the world, but the Americans haven't won in fifteen years.
Jason Blake, played by Josh Holloway.
Dante, played by Laz Alonso.
Franklyn, played by Josh Peck.
Stacy, played by Caity Lotz.
Rooster, played by Chris Brown.
Flipz, played by Ivan 'Flipz' Velez.
Battle of the Year is a 2013 American dance film directed by Benson Lee.
The film stars Josh Holloway, Chris Brown, Laz
Alonso, Caity Lotz, and Josh Peck.
It is based upon Lee's award-winning 2007 documentary Planet B-Boy,
about the b-boying competition Battle of the Year.
The feature film includes cinematography by Vasco Nunes, Lee's
director of photography on the original documentary.
The film was released theatrically on September 20,
2013 by Sony Pictures Releasing.
It received negative reviews from critics, and grossed
$16 million against a budget of $20M.
The tone is emotional.